zippo.com 2018-12-28

# U.S.A. Privacy Policy | Zippo.com

**Effective Date:  01/30/17**

**1\. ZIPPO MANUFACTURING COMPANY**

Zippo Manufacturing Company respects the privacy concerns of its customers and users of its Sites and has created this privacy statement to explain how we use and protect your personal information. We take reasonable efforts to protect any information you give us. 

**2\. CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS**

California residents who have a business relationship with ZIPPO may choose to opt-out of ZIPPO disclosing personal information to third parties for marketing purposes. ZIPPO may share any personal information you have given it with carefully screened companies that offer products or services that we believe you may enjoy. If you do not want us to share your personal information with such third parties, please send your name, address and phone number to [consumerrelations@zippo.com](mailto:consumerrelations@zippo.com "Contact Zippo"). 

**3\. COLLECTION AND USE OF INFORMATION**

Information is sometimes required for usage of the Sites, including purchase of an item or some service, or is requested from you for a particular use or purpose which we will inform you about at the time of use Your usage of the various Sites determines what information is collected. Any information that you do decide to give us will be used by us to improve your service and provide promotions and offers from ZIPPO, its subsidiaries, and promotional partners to you.

If you visit our Sites and wish to register, enter a contest or sweepstakes, purchase products, obtain information regarding one of our products or services or request other information such as Consumer Relations assistance or otherwise communicate with us about our offerings, then we will request some personally identifiable information from you.

Personally identifiable information is any information relating to a natural person that can be used to identify them from that information by reference to an identification number or some other factor specific to identity. The personally identifiable information we collect about you on certain Sites can include your name, address, telephone number, cell phone number, birth date, email address, and financial information like your credit card number and expiration date. Information submitted, other than financial information, at the time of registration or during a submission may be used for marketing and promotional purposes by ZIPPO and its subsidiaries, and may be shared with our promotional partners.

The information is also used to get in touch with you when necessary regarding an order you have placed on a Site or to notify you if you have won a contest or sweepstake.

Financial information that is collected is used to process your request for products and services, and will not be shared with third parties who are not involved with the transaction. When credit card information is transmitted, we use industry standard, SSL (secure socket layer) encryption. Due to normal legal and auditing requirements, partial credit card information is retained by us in an encrypted form. That information is not shared with any partner or any person unnecessary for legal and auditing purposes. Please see below for more information.

ZIPPO may disclose your personally identifiable information in special situations when we have reason to believe this information is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference (either intentionally or unintentionally) with ZIPPO's rights or property, other ZIPPO Site users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. In addition, ZIPPO may use personally identifiable information to conduct other legitimate activities, such as protecting the security of its Sites and its networks, guarding against potential liability, engaging in debt collection, responding to a court order or subpoena, preventing fraud, complying with law, and complying with a legally permitted inquiry by a government agency or regulator. To the extent that any of our Sites have additional or different practices or policies, these practices will be explained on that Site.

To modify or delete the information you have provided during registration, please login and update your profile. You may always opt-out of receiving future mailings by clicking on the Unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email or sending an email to[ consumerrelations@zippo.com](mailto:consumerrelations@zippo.com) with a copy of the email attached to the request and statement of your desire to be removed from the mailing list. See the Choice/Opt-out section below.

**4\. SAFEGUARD YOUR USERNAME/PASSWORD**

You are responsible for any actions that take place while using your ZIPPO account. Keep your username/password secure and do not allow anyone else to use your username/password to access the Site. You agree to notify ZIPPO at [ consumerrelations@zippo.com](mailto:consumerrelations@zippo.com) or (888)-442-1932 immediately of any unauthorized use of your ZIPPO account. ZIPPO is not responsible for any loss that results from the unauthorized use of your username/password, with or without your knowledge. 

**5\. SECURITY**

Security for all personally identifiable information is extremely important to us. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, ZIPPO cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or is transmitted to you from our online products or services. All information is stored in a secure location behind a firewall with limited administrative access. However, you transmit information to us and receive information at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

**6\. FOR PARENTS CONCERNING PRIVACY**

Zippo complies with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). See: [www.ftc.gov](http://www.ftc.gov/). In addition to any other age restrictions on this Site, please note that our Sites are not intended for children under 13 years of age, which is the age group protected under COPPA. In addition to any other age restriction on this Site, no one under age 13 may provide any information on the Sites.  We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13.

**7\. USE OF COOKIES AND PIXEL TAGS**

Zippo receives and records information from your browser when you use any of our websites and may use a variety of methods, such as “Cookies” and “Pixel Tags” to collect this information. For more information, please refer to our [Cookie Policy.  ](https://www.zippo.com/pages/cookie-policy "Zippo.com Cookie Policy")

**8\. USE OF IP ADDRESSES**

An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer by your internet provider whenever you are surfing the web. When you request pages from ZIPPO Sites, our servers log your IP address. ZIPPO collects IP addresses for the purposes of system administration, to report aggregate information to our partners, and to audit the use of our Site. Unless you purchase something we do not link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable, which means that your session will be logged, but you are anonymous to us. If you access the Buy feature in the online store, we will link your IP address to your credit card information as part of our fraud prevention program. We do this to protect you. We may use your IP addresses in cooperation with your internet provider to identify you if we feel it is necessary to enforce compliance with our Terms of Use or to protect our service, Sites, customers, or others.

**9\. MOBILE SERVICES**

The Sites contains services and features that are available to certain mobile phones. Your carrier’s normal rates and fees apply. Not all mobile services will work with all carriers or devices. You should check the rates and services offered by your carrier. By using a mobile phone to access ZIPPO Sites, you agree that that certain information about your use of these services may be shared with us through third party partners.

**10\. CHOICE/OPT-OUT**

Our Sites may provide you the opportunity to opt-in to receive communications from us at the point where we request information about you. If you receive a communication and would like to opt-out and remove your name from any future communication, follow the specific instructions outlined within the communication you receive. However, if you are unable to complete the process indicated in the communication, send an email to [ consumerrelations@zippo.com](mailto:consumerrelations@zippo.com) with a copy of the email attached to the request and statement of your desire to be removed from the mailing list. Your opt-out request will be processed within 10 days of the date it is received.

**11\. LINKS TO OTHER SITES**

ZIPPO is not responsible for the content or practices of third party websites that may be linked to our Sites. Our Sites may also be linked to websites operated by other companies. Visitors to these websites should refer to each website's respective privacy policies and practices.

**12.CONTACT US**

If you have any questions about the Terms of Use, Terms of Service, Privacy Policy, the practices of our Sites or your dealings with our Sites, contact:

> **Zippo  Consumer Relations**
> 
> 33 Barbour Street
> 
> Bradford PA, 16701
> 
> Phone: (814) 368-2700

**13.  CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

﻿It is our policy to post any changes we make to our privacy policy on this page.  If we make material changes to how we treat our users' personal information, we will notify you through a notice on this page.  The date the privacy policy was last revised is identified at the top of this page.  You are responsible for periodically visiting our Site and this privacy policy to check for any changes.  

Information provided by you via general email inquiries to ZIPPO, such as your email address, is used only to respond to your inquiries in the ordinary course of business, and is never shared with third parties.

To view educational material on consumer privacy, please see [ www.ftc.gov](http://www.ftc.gov/).
